A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Catalogued Reports, Reports 9287-11774 FA739D
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Interim report on the expanded Women's Program final version (Reports 009790), 1981 (Box 402)
  18 p., tables -- 28 cm.
  Women -- Services for -- Endowments; Women -- United States -- Endowments
- The issue before the court: Who gets ahead in America? (Reports 009791-001), 1977; Bundy, McGeorge (Box 402)
  Discusses The Regents of the University of California v. Allan Bakke prior to the ruling.'The case revolves around one white man's claim t hat he was discriminated against in favor of blacks, but far more is at stake in the deliberations now getting under
  37 p.
  Minorities -- Education; Discrimination in education -- Law and legislation; Reverse discrimination -- Law and legislation
- The issues before the court: who gets ahead in America? Nov. (Reports 009791-002), 1977; Bundy, McGeorge
  'The case revolves around one white man's claim that he was discriminated against in favor of blacks, but far more is at stake in the deliberations now getting under way before the Supreme Court of the United States. Is America ever really going to be the
  Atlantic online
  Affirmative action programs -- Law and legislation; Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education; Bakke, Allan Paul -- Trials, litigation, etc.
- March 29th discussion of initial plans for a Foundation conference on the Bakke case and affirmative action in education (Reports 009792), 1977; Payton, Benjamin Franklin, 1932- (Box 402)
  Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education; Affirmative action programs in education
- Memorandum for participants in May 4-5 meeting at the Ford Foundation regarding the under-representation of minorities in higher education (Reports 009793), 1977; Howe, Harold, II (Box 402)
  20 p. + attachments.
- Minority admissions and performance in graduate study: A preliminary study of fellowship programs of the Ford Foundation and the Danforth Foundation (Reports 009794), 1977; Payton, Benjamin Franklin, 1932-; Hartnett, Rodney T. (Box 402)
- Six-month report on the Women's Program DAP (Reports 009795), 1981 (Box 402)
  Women -- Services for -- Ford Foundation
- A preliminary evaluation: the Ford Foundation-American Institute of Architects scholarship program (Reports 009796), 1975; Parsons, Kermit C. (Kermit Carlyle), 1927- (Box 402)
  Education, Higher; Minorities -- Education, Higher
- Program evaluation: Education and Research Division (Reports 009797), 1976 (Box 402)
  An information paper for the Education Committee of the Ford Foundation Trustees.
  6 p. + attachement.
- Program support of selected black colleges in the Higher Education an Minority Affairs Program (Reports 009798), 1977 (Box 402)
- Progress report of PPSO task force on the military and society (Reports 009799), 1980; Schoettle, Enid C. B., 1939- (Box 402)
  Education and Public Policy (EPP)/Public Policy and Social Organization;Education and Public Policy (EPP)/Public Policy and Social Organization
  Public policy and social organization; Military service
- Rope production by village women (Reports 009800), undated; Sarin, Madhu (Box 402)
  Women -- India; Artisans -- India
- Six who wanted to -- enough (Reports 009801), undated; Sabine, Gordon A. (Box 402)
  A report regarding college recruitment of minority students.
- Summary of conference on strengthening graduate education and increasing the opportunity for American minorities (Reports 009802), 1977 (Box 402)
  Minorities -- Education, Higher -- United States; Universities and colleges -- United States -- Graduate work; Education, Higher -- United States
- The third minority: Ford Foundation assistance to Puerto Ricans (Reports 009803), 1975; Pandolfi, Joyce Verhalen (Box 402)
  Economic assistance -- Puerto Rico; Endowments -- Puerto Rico -- Evaluation
- Notes toward a study of the Latin American university (Reports 009804), 1967; Keegan, Frank L. (Box 402)
  Universities and colleges -- Latin America; Education, Higher -- Research -- Latin America
- Overseas compensation study (Reports 009805), 1969; Nelson, Courtney (Box 402)
  7 p. + attachments: tables, graphs -- 28 cm.
  Employment in foreign countries; Charitable uses, trusts, and foundations -- United States -- Administration
- Summaries of Ford Foundation in Argentina, Brazil, Chile, Colombia, Peru, Uruguay and Venezuela (Reports 009806), 1968 (Box 402)
  Briefs prepared for President Bundy on eve of his trip to Latin America in Jan. 1969.
  Ford Foundation programs -- Latin America
- Middle East and North Africa Review Conference, June 20-21, 1972: conference objectives and procedures (Reports 009807) (Box 402)
  L72-236.
  12 p. + attachment -- 28 cm.
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Charity organization -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa, North; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa Review Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- The Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa, June 20-21 (Reports 009808), 1972 (Box 402)
  7 p. + attachments: principally tables, maps, charts -- 28 cm.
- Human resources: quantitative and qualitative aspects (Reports 009809), 1972; Shorter, Frederic Claiborne (Box 402)
  Paper for Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa.
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
  Population -- Middle East; Population -- Africa, North
- Strengthening sustainable forest management and livelihoods to build community assets and protect upland areas and strengthening sustainable grassland management and livelihoods to build community assets and protect arid areas (POM), January 26, 2006 / (Reports 009810), Bain, Irene (Box 402)
  Asset Building and Community Development Program (ASSETS)/Community and Resource Development
  18, 18 p. (irregular pagination), tables, maps -- 28 cm.
  Program Officer Memo;POM
  Sustainable development -- China; Economic development -- Environmental aspects -- China; Forestry and community -- China; Natural resources -- China -- Management; Grassland conservation -- China
- Implications for Foundation strategy of the Rand study on economic development and population growth in the Middle East (Reports 009811), 1972; Wagner, Lewis Evern, 1924- (Box 402)
  50 p. -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Research -- Middle East; Population assistance -- Middle East; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa Review Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- Management development in Turkey: 1952 (Reports 009812), 1972; Kerwin, Robert (Robert W.) (Box 403)
  L72-236
  25 p. -- 28 cm.
  Industrial management -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Turkey; Executives -- Training of -- Turkey; Executives -- Supply and demand -- Turkey; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa Review Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- The Foundation program in the Middle East (Reports 009813), 1972; Kingsley, J. Donald (John Donald), 1908-1972 (Box 403)
  Charity organization -- Middle East; Charity organization -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa, North
- MEA and population growth in the Middle East and North Africa: 1963-1972 (Reports 009814), Irelan, William T. (Box 403)
  International Division/Middle East and Africa;International Division/Middle East and Africa
  23 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Birth control -- Africa, North; Birth control -- Middle East; Endowments -- Africa, North -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Middle East -- Evaluation
- The Palestine problem and the development process in the Middle East (Reports 009815), 1972; Peretz, Don, 1922- (Box 403)
  27 p. -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Palestine; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa Review Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- Middle Eastern oil and the western world: prospects and problems (Reports 009816), 1972; Schurr, Sam H. (Box 403)
  23 p.: table -- 28 cm.
  Petroleum industry and trade -- Middle East; Petroleum industry and trade -- Africa, North; Petroleum reserves -- United States; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa Review Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- Development opportunities in North Africa and the Middle East and the role of the World Bank Group (Reports 009818), 1972; Payson, Michael H. (Box 403)
  Paper from Ford Foundation Review Conference on the Middle East and North Africa.
  22 leaves + attachments: tables -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Africa, North; Economic development -- Middle East; Technical assistance -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Middle East; World Bank Group; International Division Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N; World Bank; International Division Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- The Saudi Arabian experience: a cooperative effort for achieving development (Reports 009819), 1972; Stucky, Conrad C. (Box 403)
  25 leaves + attachments: charts -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Saudi Arabia; Agriculture -- Economic aspects -- Saudi Arabia
- North Africa: Background: New York University (Reports 009820), 1972; Zartman, I. William (Box 403)
  Natural resources -- Africa, North
- Agricultural resources and agricultural peoples of the Middle East: past, present, and future (Reports 009821), 1972; Clawson, Marion (Box 403)
  Agriculture -- Middle East
- Problems in the realization of development potentials (Reports 009822), 1972; Bloom, Clark C. (Box 403)
  24 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Economic development -- Middle East; Central planning -- Middle East
- The special case of Israel (Reports 009823), 1972; Scott, Thomas D. (Box 403)
  17 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Endowments -- Israel -- Evaluation; Technical assistance -- Israel; International relations
- The Foundation's Middle East program: 1958-1963 (Reports 009824), 1972; Ward, F. Champion (Box 403)
  6 p. -- 28 cm.
- Beginnings of the Foundation's program in North Africa (Reports 009825), 1972; Sutton, Francis X. (Francis Xavier) (Box 403)
  14 p. -- 28 cm.
  Charity organization -- Africa, North; Technical assistance -- Africa, North
- Hill to Hall on the art of giving money away (Reports 009826), 1972; Hill, Rey M. (Box 403)
  Letter to Harvey Hall, dated March 1, 1972.
  10 p. -- 28 cm.
  Letter on the art of giving money away ...
  Economic assistance -- Developing countries; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Charity organization -- Developing countries; Ford Foundation. Middle East and Africa Review Conference (1972 June 20-21: New York, N.Y.)
- The Ford Foundation in the Middle East and North Africa, 1952-1971 draft (Reports 009827), 1972; Hall, Harvey (Box 403)
  Background on the Middle East and North Africa and Foundation activities in the region.
  85 p. -- 28 cm.
  Philanthropy -- Middle East; Philanthropy -- Africa, North; Middle East -- Endowments
- Research, scholarship, and cultural development October 1971. (Reports 009828) (Box 403)
  Notes from Education Session, International Division Conference, New Delhi, October 25-29, 1971.
  L71-23.
  18 leaves -- 28 cm.
  Cultural property -- Protection -- Developing countries; Social sciences -- Research -- Developing countries
- Resource management and environmental problems in Southeast Asia (Reports 009829), 1971; Conway, Gordon; Romm, Jeff (Box 403)
  64 p. -- 28 cm.
  Environmental management -- Southeast Asia; Natural resources -- Southeast Asia -- Management
- The Ford Foundation's program in India, Nepal, and Ceylon (Reports 009830-001), 1971; Geithner, Peter F. (Box 403)
  This paper is included in "The Ford Foundation International Division Conference."
  PAPER Conference (1971 Oct. 25-29: New Delhi, India)
  International Division; PAPER Conference (1971 Oct); Developing countries; International Division
- The Ford Foundation International Division Conference: New Delhi, India, October 25-29 (Reports 009830-002), 1971 (Box 403)
  Technical assistance -- India; Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- India -- Evaluation; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation; Philanthropy -- India; Philanthropy -- Developing countries
- Major conclusions of the International Division discussions, October 14-15 (Reports 009831), 1971 (Box 403)
  Technical assistance -- Developing countries; Endowments -- Developing countries -- Evaluation
- A summary statistical review of education in the world (Reports 009832), 1971; Goldstone, Leonard A.; International Commission on the Development of Education (Box 403)
  L71-23
  25 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Series A: situation no. 1
  Education -- Statistics; Education -- Research
- International Division Conference, New Delhi, Thursday, October 28, 1971: education, January 1972. (Reports 009833) (Box 403)
  Discussion of where to direct Foundation support to other countries.
  International Division;India, Nepal and Sri Lanka
  Philanthropy -- Developing countries; International Division
- Should Eastern Europe be considered as a less-developed area? (Reports 009834), 1971; Korbonski, Andrzej (Box 403)
  Technical assistance -- Europe, Eastern; Endowments -- Europe, Eastern -- Evaluation
- Management issues and the family planning programs of Korea, Taiwan and Malaysia: problems and opportunities for linkages to local management resources: a trip report, March 27 - April 12 (Reports 009835), 1972; Helbig, Donald W. (Box 403)
  L72-173.
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 12-16: Helsing²r, Denmark)
- Summary of argument: education and training for public policymaking: a program strategy paper for the Ford Foundation (Reports 009836), 1972; Fleishman, Joel L. (Box 403)
  L72-173
  13 p. -- 28 cm
  Public administration -- United States; Professional employees in government -- United States; Government productivity -- United States
- Management and population programs: Report of a visit to Thailand and the Philippines (Reports 009837), 1972; Farley, John U.; Leavitt, J. (Box 403)
  PAPER Conference (1972 June 12-15: Helsing²r, Denmark)
- Market and marketing research in family planning (Reports 009838), 1972; Farley, John U. (Box 403)
- Management problems of the family planning and population program in Egypt (Reports 009839), 1965; Croley, H. T. (Box 403)
- Systems analysis in family planning programming: Carnegie-Mellon University (Reports 009840), 1972; Blumstein, Alfred (Box 403)
- The use of cases and other teaching tools to improve family planning program management (Reports 009841), 1972; Jain, Sagar C. (Box 403)
- The role of institutes of public administration in population and family planning programs (Reports 009842), 1971; Summerskill, John. (Box 404)
  62 p.
- Excerpts from population program assistance (Reports 009843), 1971; United States. Agency for International Development (Box 404)
  Population; United States. Agency for International Development
- Program evaluation as a management tool: both technology and a state of mind (Reports 009844), 1972; Helbig, Donald W. (Box 404)
- Administrative concerns in family planning in six developing countries (Reports 009845), 1971; Summerskill, John. (Box 404)
- The planning-operation-evaluation cycle in family planning program administration: a management problem (Reports 009846), 1972; Reynolds, Jack, 1935- (Box 404)
- Management problems of family planning and population programs: observations by Foundation staff and consultants (Reports 009847), 1972; Gwatkin, Davidson R. (Box 404)
- Excerpts from tentative work plan: a forward look at the strategy, role and financial requirements of UNFPA (Reports 009848), 1972; United Nations (Box 404)
  *United Nations Fund for Population Activities.
  Population; United Nations
- Management and family planning (Reports 009849), 1972; Population Council (Box 404)
- Report on family planning management improvement in Central America and Mexico (Reports 009850), 1972; Ready, R. K. (Box 404)
- The Ford Foundation and "population management" in Turkey (Reports 009851), 1972; Irelan, William T. (Box 404)
  International Division/Population Program;International Division/Population Program
  10 leaves + appendices -- 28 cm.
  Population research -- Study and teaching (Higher) -- Turkey; Birth control -- Turkey
- The ernakulam vasectomy campaigns: Michigan State University (Reports 009852), 1972; Rogers, Everett M. (Box 404)
  This is chapter two of book entitled, Field experiments on family planning incentives.
  Vasectomy; Population; Birth control
- Management problems of family planning programs in the Philippines (Reports 009853), 1972; Lopez, Mario (Box 404)
  Population -- Philippines -- Congresses
- Management of family planning in India: a critique (Reports 009854), 1972; Barat, N. (Box 404)
  20 p. + appendices.
- The administration of family planning programs (Reports 009855), 1972; Cornejo M., Gerardo (Cornejo Murrieta) (Box 404)
- Summary of findings of the resources for the future study for the Commission on Population Growth and the American Future. (Reports 009856), 1972 (Box 404)
- Woman's new economic commandments (Reports 009857), 1972; Schultz, Theodore W. (Theodore William), 1902-1998 (Box 404)
- Scope and function of a population planning unit (Reports 009858), 1972; Merrick, Thomas William (Box 404)
- Effect of population change on the attainment of educational goals in the developing countries (Reports 009859), 1971; Jones, Gavin W. (Box 404)
- Population as a social science problem (Reports 009860), 1972; Silvert, Kalman H. (Box 404)
- The Population Council's International Committee for Contraception Research (Reports 009861), 1972; Harkavy, Oscar; Mahoney, Richard T.; Schearer, S. Bruce (Box 404)
- Foundation support of training in reproductive biology (Reports 009862), 1972; Mahoney, Richard T. (Box 404)
- Recent developments in contraceptive research (Reports 009863), 1972; Southam, Anna L., 1915- (Box 404)
- Foundation support of reproductive biology: new directions for the 70's? (Reports 009864), 1972; Harkavy, Oscar; Mahoney, Richard T. (Box 404)
- Other issues: a view from India (Reports 009865), 1972; Cool, John C., 1926- (Box 404)
  Foundation strategy for population work in the 70s: III
- Relevant activities of other donor agencies in the social sciences in Latin America (Reports 009866), 1972; Nagel, John S. (Box 404)
  Population -- Research
- Report for Elsinore session on social science (Reports 009867), 1972; Saunders, Lyle (Box 404)
- Population related social science research in the Middle East and Africa status report: (Reports 009868), 1972; Irelan, William T. (Box 404)
  Population research -- Middle East; Population research -- Africa
- Status report on Latin America: comparative social research on problems relevant to population policy (Reports 009869), 1972; Simmons, Ozzie G. (Box 404)
  9 p. + attachement.
- Issues in introducing into the school system education approaches to population problems: viewed for the perspective of the educational community: the case of Peru (Reports 009870), 1972; Drysdale, Robert S. (Box 404)
- The Philippine population education program and its antecedents (Reports 009871), 1972; Chauls, Donald, 1939- (Box 404)
- Letter to Robert S. Wickham (Reports 009872), 1972; Brown, Jerry L. (Box 404)
- In-school sex education, family life education and population education in Colombia: a case study in the future tense (Reports 009873), 1972; Blomberg, Robert C. (Box 404)
- A case study on the development of school population education: the Tjikini Foundation School in Indonesia (Reports 009874), 1972; Kline, David, 1950- (Box 404)
- Population education in the schools: status and needs (Reports 009875), 1972; Viederman, Stephen. (Box 404)
- Issues and problems in introducing population education (Reports 009876), 1971; Wayland, Sloan, 1918- (Box 404)
- Toward population education in Tunisia (Reports 009877), 1972; Mueller, Elisabeth, 1926- (Box 404)
- A brief note about BEMFAM's national planning seminars (Reports 009878), 1972; McLaughlin, Robert T. (Box 404)
  Population -- Brazil
- Population education in India: a case study (Reports 009879), 1972; Cool, John C., 1926- (Box 404)
- The Athoor experience: implications for a statewide family planning program (Reports 009880), 1972; Pisharoti, K. A.; Ranganathan, K. V. K.; Raman, S. (Sethu); Dutt, R. Palme (Rajani Palme), 1896-1974 (Box 404)
  Includes, "On the family program in India with special reference to Ghandigram", by Philip M. Hauser, University of Chicago, May 1970.
  21 p. + attachment.
- Variables affecting the population policies of West African governments (Reports 009881), 1972; Gwatkin, Davidson R. (Box 404)
- Report of the President: the difficulty of being earnest (Reports 009882), 1971; Berelson, Bernard, 1912-1979 (Box 405)
  This article is the Population Council's Annual Report, 1970.
- Establishing a balance between family planning services and communications activities (Reports 009883), 1972; McLaughlin, Robert T. (Box 405)
  Population -- Brazil; Birth control -- Brazil
- Population education in the context of national family planning programs (Reports 009884), 1971; Wayland, Sloan, 1918- (Box 405)
- Population education for the older generation: Some thoughts on the problem of influencing policy makers (Reports 009885), 1972; Cool, John C., 1926- (Box 405)
- A synopsis of events leading to the development of a population policy in Malaysia (Reports 009886), 1972; Saunders, Lyle
- Population and the American future (Reports 009887), 1972 (Box 405)
- Summary of Population Council activities in information and education January 1970 (Reports 009888), 1972; Population Council (Box 405)
  Population; Population Council
- Ghana's national family planning programme: a case study of public information activities (Reports 009889), 1972; Carlson, Bruce D. (Box 405)
- Advertising family planning (Reports 009890), 1971; Elliott, Robin (Box 405)
- Letter to Robert Wickham (Reports 009891), 1972; Brewer, Michael F. (Box 405)
- Isfahan mass communications project: End of project report (Reports 009892), 1970; Loghmani, M.; Gillespie, Robert (Box 405)
- Recruitment of family planning acceptors: experiences in the Population Council's international postpartum program (Reports 009893), 1972; Chapple, Martha F. (Box 405)
- Information, education, and communication in Taiwan's family planning program (Reports 009894), 1972; Tsai, Jeff; Hsu, Yvonne (Box 405)
  This paper was originally prepared for two family planning and communications workshops in 1972.
  Population -- Taiwan -- Congresses
- An aggregate analysis of population policy formation: The case of family planning in Latin America, Africa and Asia (Reports 009895), 1972; Rogers, Everett M. (Box 405)
  Population policy -- Latin America; Population policy -- Africa; Population policy -- Asia
- The Thailand project in functional literacy and family planning (Reports 009896), 1972; World Education (Organization: U.S.) (Box 405)
  Birth control -- Study and teaching -- Thailand; Population assistance -- Thailand
- Population learning and out-of-school youth in India (Reports 009897), 1971; Poffenberger, Thomas, 1921- (Box 405)
  The original version of this paper was presented at the Conference on Population Education for the Younger Generation, Manipal, India, February 14-18, '71.
- Review of the Foundation's population work in Asia (Reports 009898), 1972; Bunker, Samuel E. (Box 405)
  This paper contains various memos, letters and drafts by Bunker and other FF staff.
- Foundation assistance to Latin American education in the seventies (Reports 009899), 1972; Frodin, Reuben (Box 405)
  28 leaves: tables -- 28 cm.
  Education -- Latin America; Education and state -- Latin America; Educational assistance -- Latin America; Endowments -- Latin America -- Evaluation
- Ideological premises of western research in the field of population policy (Reports 009900), 1972; Pradervand, Pierre (Box 405)